## **Rong Zhuang**

202 Calvert DR, APT 224, Cupertino, CA 95014 Phone: (650) 380-4437 Email: jojozhuang@gmail.com Personal Website: http://jojozhuang.github.io/

## **Professional Summary**

10+ years of software development experience, with 5 years in product maintenance. Familiar with software development life cycle(SDLC), strong passion in new technologies, good at quick prototyping. A collaborative team player with excellent communication and documentation skills. Proficient in both SAP(5 years) and Microsoft .NET(7 years) platform. 6 years of web application development, 1 year of iOS, Android and hybrid mobile app development experience.

## **Working Experience**

SAP Ariba Developer Aug 2016 – Present

3410 Hillview Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304

- Working in Procurement Team, focus on Invoicing function of Ariba Procure-to-Pay(Buyer), using Java on Linux.
- Communicated frequently with stakeholders, worked independently and provided effective fix in time.
- Replicated one non-reproducible performance issue and solved it through log analysis with Splunk.
- Resolved one Go-live block issue(S1&P1), fixed it rapidly to keep SAP's promise to the customer.

Developer(Part Time) **DePaul University** 243 S Wabash Ave, Chicago, IL 60604 Sep 2014 – Jun 2016

- Quickly designed and built 3 prototypes with Html5, PhoneGap and Xamarin within 5 weeks to evaluate crossplatform mobile development solutions. Created the investigation document for director to make decision.
- Designed and built framework of an online video sharing website with Facebook React and ASP.NET Web API.
- Implemented online course player with two different technologies, SignalR in ASP.NET and Socket.IO in Node.js.

Senior Developer/Architect SAP Labs China Oct 2009 - Aug 2014

1001 Chenhui Road, Shanghai, China, 201203

- Led team(8 members) to finish development for China localization of SAP GTS, worked in lean/scrum model.
- Collected requirements and finalized design by discussing with customers, partners and product owner.
- Released more than 60 notes for bug fixing and function enhancement.
- Independently developed a complicate SAP Process Control Dashboard(contains 8 charts) with BOBJ Xcelsius.

Senior Software Engineer

Infosys Technologies China

Nov 2007 - Sep 2009

3000 Long Dong Avenue, Shanghai, China

- Developed modules with WPF & WCF for Microsoft MSSolve project.
- Led team(3 members) to develop a newsletter subscription web application with ASP.NET, finished all development and testing tasks within three weeks.
- Smoothly took over tough maintenance tasks from India colleagues of support team within 2 months.

Software Engineer

Amano Software Engineering Co., Ltd

Oct 2006 - Nov 2007

- 1111 Pu Dong Road(South), 14F, Shanghai, China
- Improved quality and performance of Amano Attendance System by refining the .NET source codes.
- Investigated and solved the compatible issues in the new environment (OS, Web Browser, .NET Framework etc.).

## Education

Master's Degree: Computer Programming/Programmer (GPA: 3.9)

Sep 2014 – June 2016

DePaul University - Chicago, IL, US

Coursework: Mining Big Data, Intelligent Information Retrieval, iOS Dev, Android Dev, OO programming, etc.

Bachelor's Degree: Computer Science and Technology

Sep 2000 - June 2004

East China University of Science & Technology - Shanghai, China

**Skills** 

Java & DB: Java/Sevrlet/JSP(Familiar), PL/SQL(Familiar)

ABAP/WebDynpro/SAP GUI (Proficient), Entry Page/BOBJ Dashboard(Familiar) SAP:

Front-End Javascript/jQuery/Html5/Bootstrap(Proficient), Node.Js/AngularJS/Facebook React(Familiar)

Big Data: Hadoop/MapReduce/Hive/Pig/EC2/Python(Working experience) Mobile: iOS/Android(Familiar), Cordova/Xamarin(Working experience)

Microsoft: C#/ASP.NET MVC/WinForm(Proficient), SQL Server/IIS(Familiar), Azure(Working experience)